# **Mark Getty**

## Procurement Engineer, Stf - Lockheed Martin - Mission Systems and Training (MST)

Wallingford, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Mark-Getty/e012538087d33c1f

Well-rounded background with solid experience in both the engineering and sourcing areas of a Fortune 100 company. Proficient in the management of major subcontracts, sourcing and procurement of direct material requirements, and implementation of pricing agreements. Practiced in the test and integration of complex, multi-element systems as well as writing system specifications and completing test objectives.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Procurement Engineer, Stf**

Lockheed Martin - Mission Systems and Training (MST) - September 2011 to Present

Prepare bid packages, analyze and evaluate proposals using cost and pricing data, negotiate subcontract provisions, select subcontractors, write awards, and administer resulting major software engineering subcontracts in support of government primes with multiple contract types

- Negotiate and coordinate subcontract modifications. Achieved \$1.3M in negotiated savings since 2011
- Authorized more than \$50M in work scope and funding to LM subcontractors. Only authorized interface with the subcontractor.
- Interface with multiple program management, engineering, legal, finance, and supplier contacts to coordinate subcontract direction
- Build large dollar domestic and international PO folders and oversee compliance with US government imposed Federal Acquisition Regulations, Cost Accounting Standards, and LM Acquisition Procedures
- Develop and review Statements of Work
- · Extensive experience negotiating purchases for IT hardware/software and mechanical commodities

#### **Procurement Planning & Control, Sr**

Lockheed Martin - Mission Systems and Training (MST) - November 2008 to September 2011

- Led the development of supply chain agreement strategies for various US defense programs and negotiated with key suppliers to establish pricing contracts that supported program targets and deadlines.
- Engaged in face-to-face negotiations with Lockheed Martin's supply base in order to drive material costs savings for MST programs. Group generated \$11M in material cost savings for agreement parts in 2009.
- Participated and collaborated with Global Supply Chain Organization Project Managers in the Group Purchasing Agreement process
- Created and presented negotiation strategies that impact project cost. Worked with engineers and buyers to proactively identify cost drivers
- Provided buyers with agreement support by resolving issues and implementing site agreements to assist in immediate purchasing needs
- Documented group processes for future training purposes
- Issued Purchase Orders for required MST commodity material

## Member of Engineering Staff

Lockheed Martin - Mission Systems and Training (MST) - June 2003 to November 2008

Successfully supported Lockheed Martin Foreign Military Sales through the Japan Aegis Lifetime Support program

· Updated, integrated, tested, and installed Aegis Weapon System computer programs with shipboard

equipment and combat system elements aboard the DDG173 Kongo Class of Japanese Destroyers. Included extensive international travel

- Provided Crew Briefs and training to the U.S. and Japanese Navy on the functionality of the Aegis Display System Computer Program for the Kongo Class of Japanese Destroyers
- Generated and presented several technical documents for critical use by the Japanese, Spanish, and Norwegian Navy's
- Supported software design activities, including reviewing top level and detailed level design, conducting code reviews, writing specification changes, and participating in unit level testing
- Participated in several U.S. Navy Combat System Ship Qualification Tests (CSSQTs) underway on U.S. Navy ships

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **MBA** in Finance

Drexel University March 2007

## **BS** in Electrical Engineering

Villanova University May 2003

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### **SKILLS**

- LM MST Earned Value Management Certified Completed LM's Supply Chain Leadership Institute course
- Six Sigma Green Belt Certified Excellent Interpersonal & Customer Service skills
- Strong written and oral communication skills Proficient using SAP-based purchasing system